Guide to the Paul L. Holmer Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Writings of Holmer, Series I
  - Unpublished essays / lectures
    - "Kierkegaard and Metaphysics." 1-22 (1 typescript) (Box 20, Folder 259)
    - "Kierkegaard as an Ethical Thinker." 1-39 (3 typescripts), n.d. (Box 20, Folder 259)
    - "Kierkegaard: Faith in a Tragic World." 1-17 (1 typescript, 1 typescript copy, 1 manuscript), n.d. (Box 20, Folder 260)
    - "Kierkegaard On Subjectivity: Two Concepts." 1-25 (1 typescript, related S.K. notes), n.d. (Box 20, Folder 260)
    - "Kierkegaard's Relation to Johannes Climacus." 1-13 (1 typescript), n.d. (Box 21, Folder 261)
    - "Logic and Faith." 1-3 (3 typescripts, 1 manuscript) (Box 21, Folder 263)
    - "Love on Command." 1-16 (1 manuscript, 2 computer printout, 6 copies of typescripts, 1 typescript) (Box 21, Folder 264)
    - "Luther's Criticism of Tradition." 1-5 (1 manuscript), n.d. (Box 21, Folder 265)
    - "Martin Luther: Theology and Our Culture." 1-5 (1 manuscript) (Box 21, Folder 266)
    - "Mority Schlick (1882-1936)." 1-2 (1 manuscript), n.d. (Box 21, Folder 267)
    - "Music and Religion." 1-11 (1 manuscript) (Box 21, Folder 268)
    - "The Nature of Philosophy" 1-33 (1 typescript, out of order, and interspersed with manuscript pages; 1 corrected typescript; 2 typescripts marked "Rough Draft") (Box 21, Folder 269)
    - "The Nygren-Wingren Debate Revisited." 1-3 (1 typescript) (Box 21, Folder 270)
    - "No Other Foundation." 1-23 (3 copies of typescripts, 1 computer printout, 1 manuscript) (Box 21, Folder 271)
    - "On Being Godly." 1-6 (4 typescript copies, 2 computer printouts, 1 manuscript), n.d. (Box 21, Folder 272)
    - "On Being a Christian and a Scholar." 1-2 (1 typescript, 1 manuscript) (Box 21, Folder 273)
    - "On Believing in the Scriptures." 1-6 (1 typescript, 1 manuscript), n.d. (Box 21, Folder 274)
    - "On Grief and Grieving." 1-4 (1 copy of typescript) (Box 21, Folder 275)
    - "On Referring." 1-5 (1 copy of typescript, notes: "'Meaning' and the Confusion it Generates," "Frege," "Language and Reality," "Ambiguity and Obscurity," "Systematic Ambiguity," "The Semantic or Meta-Linguistic Theory of Truth," "Phil. Theology and Concept Analysis," "Grammar of the World," "On Referring"; syllabus: "Philosophical Theology Seminar" ) (Box 21, Folder 276)
    - "Philosophy and Religion." 1-65 (1 typescript, 2 corrected copies of typescript, 1 manuscript) (Box 21, Folder 278)
    - "Problems of Meaning and Interpretation." 1-31 (1 manuscript) (Box 21, Folder 279)
    - "Recent Philosophy and Supernaturalism." 1-24 (4 typescripts, 1 manuscript and typescript) (Box 21, Folder 280)
    - "The Referents of Mentalistic Predicates" 1-11 (1 typescript), n.d. (Box 22, Folder 281)
    - "Religion and Curriculum." 1-12 (1 typescript) (Box 22, Folder 282)
    - "Religion and Knowledge," (1 manuscript); "Religion as Knowledge," (1 typescript); "Religion as Faith," (1 typescript); "Religion as Love," (1 typescript); "Religion and Doubt," (1 typescript). (Box 22, Folder 283)
    - "Remarks about Paradox." 1-13 (2 typescripts), n.d. (Box 22, Folder 284)
    - "Remarks about Christian Education." 1-18 (3 typescripts), n.d. (Box 22, Folder 285)
    - "A Review of the McGill University Faculty and Program of Religious Studies." 1-12 (2 typescript, 2 manuscripts) (Box 22, Folder 286)
    - "Saint Augustine and Greek Thought" (Box 22, Folder 286)
    - "The Scandal of Theology." 1-16 (1 typescript, 2 manuscripts) (Box 22, Folder 287)
    - "Science and Theology." 1-16 (3 typescripts, 2 copies of typescripts) (Box 22, Folder 288)
    - "The Scriptures and Their Role" 1-22 (1 manuscript, 2 typescripts, 1 computer printout) (Box 22, Folder 289)
    - "The Scripture and the Twentieth Century" (possibly a chapter of a book?) 1-27 (1 manuscript, 1 typescript, 1 printout, 1 extra page 1) (Box 22, Folder 290)
    - "Sheldon on God and Reality." 1-7 (2 typescripts, 1 typescript copy, 1 manuscript) (Box 22, Folder 291)
    - "Something About David Sandstrom and His Book." (n.d.) 1-3 (3 typescripts) (Box 22, Folder 293)
    - "Strangers to God." (n.d.) 1-12 (1 typescript, 2 typescript copies, 1 manuscript) (Box 22, Folder 294)
    - "Theology and Forming Consciousness." (n.d.) 1-18 (1 typescript) (Box 22, Folder 295)
    - "Theology and Knowing God." (n.d.) (1 manuscript, 1 copy of manuscript, 1 copy of typescript) (Box 22, Folder 296)
    - "Theology and Liturgy." (n.d) 1-13 (1 typescript) (Box 22, Folder 297)
    - "Theology, Ideology and Social Questions: The Predicament and the Task." (n.d.) 1-32 (2 typescripts) (Box 22, Folder 298)
    - "Theological and Philosophical Kierkegaard Studies in Scandinavia, 1945-53." (nd.) 1-19 (4 typescripts, 1 manuscript, 1 set of stencils) (Box 22, Folder 299)
    - "Theological Education and Personal Faith." (n.d) 1-32 (1 typescript) (Box 22, Folder 300)
    - "Theology and Understanding." (n.d.) 1-16 (1 typescript) (Box 23, Folder 301)
    - "Thought and Its Varieties." (n.d.) 1-2 (1 typescript) (Box 23, Folder 302)
    - Tillich essay. (n.d.) 1-25 (1 typescript); Strindberg essay. (n.d.) 1-8 (1 typescript); misc. notes. (Box 23, Folder 303)
    - "Trinity and Language: A Critical Note." (n.d.) 1-5 (1 edited typescript, 1 galley copy of Paul Lehmann's "The Tri-Unity of God," letter from Chuck Powers [of Union Seminary Quarterly Review ) (Box 23, Folder 304)
    - "An Unenlightened Zeal." Unpublished. 1-11 (1 manuscript, 5 copies of typescript with edits) (Box 23, Folder 305)
    - "The University, Philosophy and Theology." (n.d.) 1-11 (1 computer printout) (Box 23, Folder 306)
    - "Until I Went Into the Sanctuary of God." (n.d) 1-10 (1 typescript, 1 copy of typescript) (Box 23, Folder 307)
    - "The Use of the Bible in the Life of Faith and in Devotion." (n.d.) 1-15 (typescript) (Box 23, Folder 308)
    - "Virtues and Vices." (n.d.) 1-25 (1 typescript) (Box 23, Folder 309)
    - "US Religion Americanized?" (n.d.) 1 (3 newspaper article clippings) (Box 23, Folder 310)
    - "What Do We Gain By All the Toil?" (n.d.) 1-4 (1 manuscript) (Box 23, Folder 311)
    - "Wittgenstein and Kierkegaard." (n.d.) 1-12 (1 computer printout, 1 essay entitled "Names and Concepts") (Box 23, Folder 312)
    - "What is God Like?" (n.d) 1-10 (4 typescripts) (Box 23, Folder 313)
    - "What Must We Do?" (n.d.) 1-9 (1 typescript copy with edits) (Box 23, Folder 314)
    - "What Religious Groups Can Contribute to a Campus." (n.d.) 1-6 (1 typescript) (Box 23, Folder 315)
    - "Wittgenstein and Linguistic Idealism." (n.d.) 1-3 (1 typescript) (Box 23, Folder 316)
    - "Wittgenstein and the Self." (n.d.) 1-32 (2 typescripts) (Box 23, Folder 317)
    - "Wittgenstein, Kierkegaard: The Subjective Thinker." (n.d.) 1-12 (1 manuscript copy) (Box 23, Folder 318)
    - "Wittgenstein on Knowledge and Certainty." (n.d.) 1-36 (1 typescript copy) (Box 23, Folder 319)
    - "Wittgenstein on 'Saying' and 'Sharing'." (n.d.) 1-3 (1 manuscript, notes, Wittgenstein bibliography, "Meaning" and Wittgenstein outlines; notes: "Rules and Grammar," "Upshot of Picture Theory," "The Form of the World," "W. on 'Saying and Showing'," "Meaning and Concepts," "Wittgenstein and Theology," "About Theology.") (Box 23, Folder 320)
  - Reviews by Holmer
    - Review of Kierkegaard works: Either/Or, Vol I (David F. and Lillian Marvin Swenson, trans.); Either/Or, Vol II (Walter Lowrie, trans.); The Concept of Dread (Walter Lowrie, trans.); Training in Christianity (Walter Lowrie, trans.); For Self-Examination (Walter Lowrie, trans.); and The Attack Upon Christendom (Walter Lowrie, trans.) in The Journal of English and Germanic Philology, 44: 324-329. (journal offprints), 1945 Jul (Box 24, Folder 321)
    - Review of Kierkegaard works: Works of Love (David F. and Lillian Marvin Swenson, trans. Princeton, NJ: Princeton Press, 1946) and A Kierkegaard Anthology (Robert Bretall, ed. Princeton, NJ: Princeton Press, 1946) in The Journal of English and Germanic Philosophy, XLVI.3: 332-334. (journal offprints), 1947 Jul (Box 24, Folder 322)
    - Review of Kierkegaard works: Edifying Discourses: I-IV (David F. Swenson and Lillian Marvin Swenson, trans. Minneapolis: Augsburg, 1943-1946.) and A Kierkegaard Anthology (Robert Bretall, ed. Princeton, NJ: Princeton UP, 1946.) in The American-Scandinavian Review, 35.3: 272-274. (1 journal)., 1947 Sep (Box 24, Folder 323)
    - Review of Dreadful Freedom (Marjorie Grene. Chicago: U of Chicago P, 1948) in Philosophical Review, 58: 190-191. (3 sets of tear sheets, 1 typescript)., 1949 Mar (Box 24, Folder 324)
    - Review of Kierkegaard's Philosophy of Religion (Reidar Thomte. Princeton, NJ: Princeton UP, 1948) in The Philosophical Review, LIX.3. (journal offprints, 1 typescript of early draft), 1950 Jul (Box 24, Folder 325)
    - Review of Nietzsche: Philosopher, Psychologist, Antichrist (Walter A. Kaufmann. Princeton, N.J.: Princeton UP, 1974) in The Lutheran Quarterly, 3.4: 426-427. (2 typescripts, 1 letter from Kaufmann), 1951 Nov (Box 24, Folder 326)
    - Review of Kierkegaard Und Der Verfuhrer (Walther Rehm. Munich: Herman Rinn, 1949) and Kierkegaard the Cripple (Theodor Haecker. C. Van O. Bruyn, trans. New York: Philosophical Library, 1950) in Philosophy and Phenomenological Research, 12.2: 307-311. (2 journal offprint, 2 typescripts)., 1951 Dec (Box 24, Folder 327)
    - Review of Kierkegaard Und Der Verfuhrer (Walther Rehm. Munich: Herman Rinn, 1949) in The Philosophical Review, 61.2: 270-273. (journal offprints, 2 typescripts)., 1952 Apr (Box 24, Folder 328)
    - Review of The Development of the Soul in Medieval Jewish Philosophy (Philip David Bookstaber. Philadelphia: Maurice Jacobs, 1950) in Lutheran Quarterly, 5.2: 230-231. (1 manuscript, 1 typescript)., 1953 May (Box 24, Folder 329)
    - Review of Time and Eternity: An Essay in the Philosophy of Religion (W. T. Stace. Princeton: Princeton UP, 1952.) in The Lutheran Quarterly, 5.2: 226-229. (1 typescript, 1 manuscript)., 1953 May (Box 24, Folder 330)
    - Review of The Religious Philosophy of Josiah Royce (Stuart Gerry Brown, ed. Syracuse: Syracuse UP, 1952.) in Philosophical Review, 63: 106-110. (1 typescript, 1 manuscript, 1 journal offprint)., 1954 Jan (Box 24, Folder 331)
    - Review of Unity and Language: A Study in the Philosophy of Johann Georg Hamann (James G. O'Flaherty. Chapel Hill, NC: UNC Studies in the Germanic Languages and Literatures, 1952.) in The Lutheran Quarterly, 6.1: 83-84. (1 typescript)., 1954 Feb (Box 24, Folder 332)
    - Review of What is Religion (Alban G. Widgery. New York: Harper and Brothers, 1953) in The Lutheran Quarterly 6.1: 81-83, 1954 Feb (Box 24, Folder 333)
    - Review of The Philosophy of Wilhem Dilthey (H. A. Hodges. London: Routledge and Kegan Paul Ltd., 1952) and Languages, Standpoints, and Attitudes (H. A. Hodges. Oxford: Oxford UP, 1953) in The Christian Scholar, 37.2: 155-157). (1 manuscript, 1 typescript, 1 journal offprint), 1954 Jun (Box 24, Folder 334)
    - Review of Unity and Language: A Study in the Philosophy of Johann Georg Hamann (James G. O'Flaherty. Chapel Hill, NC: UNC Studies in the Germanic Languages and Literatures, 1952.) in The Journal of Religion, 34.3: 226-227. (2 offprints, 1 typescript, 1 manuscript)., 1954 Jul (Box 24, Folder 335)
    - "James Collins and Kierkegaard," review of The Mind of Kierkegaard (James Collins. Chicago: Henry Regnery Co., 1953.) in Reports from the Soren Kierkegaard Society. Quarterly Review, 5.1, 1-8. (1 journal, 4 journal offprints, 1 typescripts)., 1954 Aug (Box 24, Folder 336)
    - Review of Unity and Language: A Study in the Philosophy of Johann Georg Hamann (James G. O'Flaherty. Chapel Hill, NC: UNC Studies in the Germanic Languages and Literatures, 1952.) in Philosophy and Phenomenological Research, 15: 122-124. (1 typescript, 1 manuscript)., 1954 Sep (Box 24, Folder 337)
    - Review of Unity and Language: A Study in the Philosophy of Johann Georg Hamann (James G. O'Flaherty. Chapel Hill, NC: UNC Studies in the Germanic Languages and Literatures, 1952.) in Philosophical Review, 63.4: 618-619. (1 typescript, 1 manuscript)., 1954 Oct (Box 24, Folder 338)
    - "A Recondite German Philosopher," review of Unity and Language: A Study in the Philosophy of Johann Georg Hamann (James G. O'Flaherty. Chapel Hill, NC: UNC Studies in the Germanic Languages and Literatures, 1952.) in The Philosopher, 6.2: 81-83. (2 journals, 2 offprints, 1 typescript, 1 manuscript)., 1954 Nov (Box 24, Folder 339)
    - Review of Breve og Akstykker Vedrorende Soren Kierkegaard (Niels Thulstrup, ed. Copenhagen: Ejnar Munksgaard, 1953 and 1954) in Philosophy and Phenomenological Research, XV.2: 261-263. (1 journal offprint), 1954 Dec (Box 24, Folder 340)
    - Review of God and Polarity: A Synthesis of Philosophies (Wilmon H. Sheldon. New Haven: Yale UP, 1954) in Ethics, LXV.3: 224-227. (1 journal), 1955 Apr (Box 24, Folder 340)
    - Review of Johann Georg Hamann (Tage Schack. Copenhagen: Tidehvervs Forlag, 1948) in The Hamann News-Letter, 1.4: 3-4. (1 journal, 2 typescripts, 1 manuscript)., 1955 May (Box 24, Folder 341)
    - "Religious Confusion," a review of On Authority and Revelation... (Soren Kierkegaard. Walter Lowrie, trans. Princeton, NJ: Princeton UP, 1955) in Christian Century, 72: 1026. (1 journal, 1 journal page, 2 typescripts, 1 copy of typescript, 1 manuscript), 1955 Sep 7 (Box 24, Folder 342)
    - Review of Meditations from Kierkegaard (Soren Kierkegaard. T.H. Croxall, trans. Philadelphia: Westminster, 1955) in Journal of Religion, 36.4: 285. (1 manuscript, 1 typescript), 1956 Oct (Box 24, Folder 343)
    - Review of Kierkegaard Commentary (T. H. Croxall. New York: Harper and Brothers, 1956) in Christian Century, 73.49: 1423. (2 journals, 1 typescript, 1 manuscript)., 1956 Dec 5 (Box 24, Folder 344)
    - Review of The Moment Before God (Martin Heinecken. Philadelphia: Muhlenberg, 1956) in The Lutheran, 39.11: 31. (1 typescript, 3 mimeographed copies, 2 manuscript, 3 journals)., 1956 Dec 12 (Box 24, Folder 345)
    - "S. K. for Today," review of The Moment Before God (Martin Heinecken. Philadelphia: Muhlenberg, 1956) in Christian Century, 73: 1510. (2 mimeographs, 2 journals, 1 typescript, 1 manuscript)., 1956 Dec 26 (Box 24, Folder 346)
    - Review of Christianity and Symbolism (F. W. Dillistone. Philadelphia: Westminster Press, 1955) in The Lutheran Quarterly, 9.1: 77-78. (1 typescript, 1 manuscript), 1957 Feb (Box 24, Folder 347)
    - Review of A History of Modern European Philosophy (James Collins. Milwaukee: Bruce Publishing, Co., 1954) in The Lutheran Quarterly, 9.1: 92-93. (1 typescript, 1 manuscript)., 1957 Feb (Box 24, Folder 348)
    - Review of The Moment Before God (Martin Heinecken. Philadelphia: Muhlenberg, 1956) in Journal of Religion, 37: 129-30. (2 typescripts, 1 manuscript)., 1957 Apr (Box 24, Folder 349)
    - Review of On Authority and Revelation... (Soren Kierkegaard. Walter Lowrie, trans. Princeton, NJ: Princeton UP, 1955) in American Scandinavian Review, 45: 302-303). (1 journal, 2 typescripts, 2 manuscripts [one is very different from version printed in ASR or Christian Century ], partial drafts of other articles), 1957 Sep (Box 24, Folder 350)
    - Review of Subjectivity and Paradox (J. Heywood Thomas. New York: MacMillan, 1957) in Christian Century, 75: 1136. (1 journal, 1 typescript, 1 manuscript)., 1958 Nov 19 (Box 24, Folder 351)
    - Review of A Study of History (Arnold J. Toynbee. Oxford: Oxford UP, 1957) in Journal of Religion, 39.1: 59-61. (1 typescript, 1 manuscript)., 1959 Jan (Box 24, Folder 352)
    - Review of Efferfoljelsens teologi hos Soren Kierkegaard (Valter Lindstrom. Stockholm: Diakonistyrelsens Bokforlag, 1956) in Lutheran Quarterly, 11.1: 81-82. (1 typescript, 1 manuscript), 1959 Feb (Box 24, Folder 353)
    - Review of The Religions of Man (Huston Smith. New York City: Harper and Brothers, 1958) in Journal of Higher Education, 30: 116-118. (1 typescript, 1 manuscript)., 1959 Feb (Box 24, Folder 354)
    - Review of Temporal and Eternal (Charles Peguy. New York: Harper and Brothers, 1958.) in The Lutheran Quarterly, 11.3: 260-261. (1 typescript, 1 manuscript)., 1959 Aug (Box 24, Folder 355)
    - Review of An Analytical Philosophy of Religion (William F. Zuurdeeg. Nashville: Abingdon Press, 1958) in Religion in Life, 29.1: p.? (Winter, 1959-60). (3 mimeographs), 1959-1960 (Box 24, Folder 356)
    - "Science and Religion Reconsidered," review of The Promise of Science and the Power of Faith (M. Holmes Hartshorne. Philadelphia: Westminster Press, 1958) and Chance and Providence (William G. Pollard. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1958) in Lutheran World, 6: 477-450. (1 set of tear sheets); German version in Buchbesprechungen Heft 4, February 1960., 1959-1960 (Box 24, Folder 357)
    - Review of Four Existentialist Theologians: A Reader from the Work of Maritain, Berdyaev, Buber, and Tillich (Will Herberg. New York: Doubleday and Co., 1958) in The Lutheran Quarterly, 12.1: 69-70. (1 typescript, 1 copy of typescript, 1 manuscript)., 1960 Feb (Box 24, Folder 358)
    - Review of Faith and Community (Clyde A. Holbrook. New York: Harper and Bros, 1959.) in The Lutheran Quarterly, 12.2: 178-179. (2 typescripts, 1 manuscript, 3 letters)., 1960 May (Box 24, Folder 359)
    - Review of Theology of Culture (Paul Tillich. New York: Oxford UP, 1959.) in Lutheran Quarterly, 12.2: 178-179. (1 manuscript, 2 typescripts)., 1960 May (Box 24, Folder 360)
    - Review of A Genuinely Human Existence (Stephen Neill. New York: Doubleday, 1959) in Lutheran Quarterly, 12.3: 266-267. (1 typescript, 1 manuscript)., 1960 Aug (Box 25, Folder 361)
    - Review of Biblical Thought and the Secular University (George Arthur Buttrick. Baton Rouge: Louisiana State UP, 1960.) in The Intercollegian, 78.6: 23. (2 journals, 1 typescript, 1 manuscript, 1 clipping of Harry G. Goodykoontz's review of the same book)., 1961 Mar (Box 25, Folder 362)
    - "Faith and Scholarship," review of Science Ponders Religion (Harlow Shapley, ed. New York: Appleton-Century-Crofts, 1960.) and Darwin's Vision and Christian Perspectives (Walter J. Ong, S.J. New York: MacMillian, 1960.) in Saturday Review, (April 1, 1961): 14-15. (1 journal, 1 typescript, 1 manuscript)., 1961 Apr 1 (Box 25, Folder 363)
    - Review of The Theological Foundation of Law (Jacques Ellul. Marguerite Wieser, trans. New York: Doubleday, 1960) in The Lutheran Quarterly, 13.3: 274-275. (1 manuscript, 1 typescript)., 1961 Aug (Box 25, Folder 364)
    - Review of Modern Science in the Christian Life (John W. Klotz. St. Louis, MO: Concordia, 1961) in Literature Survey, n.v.: n.p. (1 journal, 1 typescript, letter from journal), 1961 Sep (Box 25, Folder 365)
    - Review of In Search of the Self (Philadelphia: Muhlenburg Press, 1962) in Dialog 1: 80. (2 typescripts [different versions], 1 manuscript, 1 letter from Dialog ), 1962 Autumn (Box 25, Folder 366)
    - Review of Theological Explanation (London: James Nisbet and Co.; Naperville, IL: Alec B. Allenson, Inc.) in Lutheran Quarterly, 15.1: 89-90. (1 typescript, 1 letter from journal staff, 1 letter from London publisher), 1963 Feb (Box 25, Folder 367)
    - Review of Kierkegaard as Theologian (Louis Dupre. New York: Sheed and Ward, 1963) in The Journal of Religion, 43.3: 255-256. (1 typescript, 1 letter from journal staff), 1963 Jul (Box 25, Folder 368)
    - Review of Kierkegaard as Theologian (Louis Dupre. New York: Sheed and Ward, 1963.) in Religious Education, 58: 404. (1 typescript, 1 piece of correspondence with journal)., 1963 Jul-Aug (Box 25, Folder 369)
    - Review of Twentieth-Century Religious Thought (John MacQuarrie. New York: Harper and Row, 1963.) in Union Seminary Quarterly Review, 19.1: n.p. (2 journal offprints, 2 manuscripts, 1 former library typescript copy)., 1963 Nov (Box 25, Folder 370)
    - Review of Religious Experience and Truth: A Symposium (Sidney Hook. New York: New York UP, 1961) in Theology Today, 20.4: 583-585. (1 manuscript, 2 typescripts, 1 journal offprint, letter from journal editor), 1964 Jan (Box 25, Folder 371)
    - Review of The Retreat to Commitment (William Warren Bartley III. New York: Knopf, 1962.) in Journal of Religion, 44: 161-163. (1 manuscript, 2 typescripts, 1 letter from Bartley)., 1964 Apr (Box 25, Folder 372)
    - Review of Morality and the Language of Conduct (Hector-Neri Castaneda and George Nakhnikian. Detroit: Wayne State UP, 1963.) in Universitas: A Journal of Religion and the University, 2.3: 110-112. (2 journals, 1 copy of journal article, 2 typescripts, 1 manuscript)., 1964 Fall (Box 25, Folder 373)
    - Review of Religion and the Public Order (Donald A. Giannella, ed. Chicago: U of Chicago P, 1964) in The Journal of Higher Education, 36.3: 175-178. (1 journal, 2 typescripts, 1 manuscript)., 1965 Mar (Box 25, Folder 374)
    - Review of The Dilemma of Contemporary Theology (Per Lonning. New York: Humanities Press, 1963) in Journal of Religion, 45.2: 167-169. (2 typescripts, 1 manuscript)., 1965 Apr (Box 25, Folder 375)
    - Review of Sermons to Intellectuals (Franklin H. Littell, ed. New York: Macmillian, 1963) in The Intercollegian, 82.7-8: 21-22. (2 typescript, 1 manuscript, 2 journals)., 1965 May-Jun (Box 25, Folder 376)
    - Review of Ministry (Robert S. Paul. Grand Rapids: Eerdmans, 1965.) in The Hartford Quarterly, 6.4: 59-61. (1 journal, 3 photocopies of journal article, 1 typescript, 1 manuscript)., 1966 Summer (Box 25, Folder 377)
    - Review of They Speak with Other Tongues (John L. Sherrill. Westwood, N.J.: McGraw-Hill, 1964.) and Pentecostalism (John T. Nichol. New York: Harper and Row, 1966.) in Lutheran Libraries, 9.3: 18. (1 journal, 1 typescript)., 1967 Summer (Box 25, Folder 378)
    - Review of Belief and Unbelief, A Philosophy of Self-Knowledge (Michael Novak. New York: Macmillian Co., 1965.) in Dialog, 6: 69-70. (1 manuscript)., 1967 Winter (Box 25, Folder 379)
    - Review of The Crisis of Piety, Essays Towards a Theology of the Christian Life (Donald G. Bloesch. Grand Rapids, MI: Eerdmans, 1968) in Christian Century, 85.45: 1407. (2 journals, 1 typescript), 1968 Nov 6 (Box 25, Folder 380)
    - Review of Kierkegaard and Radical Discipleship: A New Perspective (Vernard Eller. Princeton, NJ: Princeton UP, 1968) and Kierkegaard: An Introduction (Hermann Diem. David Green, trans. Richmond, VA: John Knox Press, 1967) Unpublished? (July, 1969, according to the original folder) [Note: A version of this review is published in The Journal for the Scientific Study of Religion, 9.1: 67-70 (Spr., 1970), but that contains different text and covers Eller only.] (1 typescript, 1 card from Interpretation ) (Box 25, Folder 381)
    - Review of Kierkegaard's Authorship: A Guide to the Writings of Kierkegaard (George E. Arbaugh and George B. Arbaugh. Rock Island, IL: Augustana College Library, 1967) in Scandinavian Studies, 41.4: 364-367. (3 journal offprints, 1 typescript, 1 letter from managing editor of journal), 1969 Nov (Box 25, Folder 382)
    - Review of Kierkegaard on Christ and Christian Coherence (Paul Sponheim. New York, Harper and Row, 1968.) in Religious Education, 64: 520. (1 typescript), 1969 Nov-Dec (Box 25, Folder 383)
    - Review of Kierkegaard on Christ and Christian Coherence (Paul Sponheim. New York, Harper and Row, 1968.) in Lutheran Forum, 3.11: 26-28. (1 corrected copy, 2 typescripts, 1 manuscript, 2 letters), 1969 Dec (Box 25, Folder 384)
    - Review of Kierkegaard's Authorship, A Guide to the Writings of Kierkegaard (George E. Arbaugh and George B. Arbaugh. Rock Island, IL: Augustana College Library, 1967) in Religious Education, 65: 222-224. (1 typescript, 1 manuscript, 1 letter from G.C. Schoolfield), 1970 Mar-Apr (Box 25, Folder 385)